Hui Koon, YEO

■ Phone: 98799721 ■ Email: bungee_07@yahoo.com.sg

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Dedicated CPA with 10+ years of finance experience working in banks and MNCs, who consistently delivers organizational goals and establishes good business relationships with key stakeholders. Possess strong analytical and interpersonal communication skills. An efficient and organized team player with ability to reach and surpass expectations.

EDUCATION

- CPA (Aust.)
- Master of Accounting, Curtin University
- Bachelor of Science in Statistics, The National University of Singapore

CORE COMPETENCIES & SKILLS

- Strong analytical skills Results oriented Personal credibility Flexible Team player
- SAP Advanced Excel and Powerpoint HP Quality Center MicroStrategy

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS

CITIBANK N.A. October 2016 to October 2017

Project Manager (CTO – Data Governance)

- Manage the CCAR (Comprehensive Capital Analytical Review) FRB regulatory project in APAC. Provide resolution plans on finance and risk data issues raised and drive to closures.
- Collaborate with Chief Data Office, Product owners, Business Solutions and Finance teams to implement and execute the Genesis Sprint project in APAC, achieving high rate of resolution.
- Effectively communicate the project scope, schedule and planning of the 1st SWAT call in Asia with the key stakeholders, including running weekly status calls and updates.
- Lead as the Data Governance Officer to manage the integrity of the finance and risk data and ensure that the defined set of procedures are properly adhered and planned out effectively in Asia.
- Initially built and subsequently prepare, review management dashboard decks with commentaries for monthly business governance forums.

THE HONGKONG AND SHANGHAI BANKING CORPORATION LTD June 2014 to July 2015

Risk Management and Reports Manager

- Design and produce the entire MI trade finance reporting suite from scratch to provide quality information to the Management and other internal stakeholders.
- Establish guidelines for budget and forecast preparation, and prepare the annual budget in

consultation with the Management and UK Finance.

- Report and active monitoring of daily credit exposures on investors' limits and ratings on transactional basis. Comply and amend risk management policies and procedures to ensure that organizational risks are minimized.
- Interpret financial information and producing accurate reports supporting the business.
- Delegate as the Business Information Risk Officer (BIRO) to ensure the team's compliance to the Bank's information security risk policies.

THE ROYAL BANK OF SCOTLAND August 2012 to June 2014

Business Unit Controller

- Conduct the strategic review process of trading books for RBS Asia Pacific Markets business including effective monitoring of books that are linked to each business and its impacts, analyzing the Profit & Loss and passing of journals.
- Lead the book closure process through strategic implementation of controls and effective collaboration with Front, Middle, Risk, Data Integrity and Static Data teams to ensure the books are closed efficiently.
- Build effective controls around approval process to reduce time resources in closing down trading books, including improving current processes and manuals setting up.
- Prepare book statistics (open & closed) performance to management on a daily basis.
- Effectively and successfully closing off on a substantial number of trading books independently within a short period of time and received recognition by superior.

Financial Controller

- Prepare the population and review of statutory reporting packs (SDPs) for 7 legal entities and ensure complete closure.
- Responsible for managing trades under Short Term Money Funding (STMF), which entails the performing of intercompany trade reconciliation and liaison with middle office and product controllers on mismatched trades.
- Provide all necessary consolidation or legal entity adjustments to ensure the appropriate reporting of the M&IB divisional financial statements, including full balance sheet substantiation and review.
- Lead as the SDP Champion for MIS5 (Balance Sheet Core & Non-Core) and CASH3 (cash flow of assets) responsible for tactical review and challenge to the business units on the variances every month.

UNITED OVERSEAS BANK LTD May 2008 to July 2012

Finance Manager

- Ensure the timely completion of month-end closing for UOB's 12 overseas subsidiaries/branches, 5 property and 7 investment holding entities.
- Prepare accurate and reliable monthly financial reports that provide meaningful analysis of variances for the Management.
- Review of consolidation packages, financial statements under IFRS and other reports and

communications to cross-departments.

- Review accounting transactions of the fund in investment entities. Review monthly closing of fund books and review periodic financial statements. Review of month-end journals and accruals.
- Provide solutions to business units' reporting request / reporting needs. Understand the cultural needs of overseas entities and provide prompt advisory support for rectifications at the same time, ensure prompt delivery of service and build cordial relationships.
- Review of accounting work performed by staff on private equity funds, including capital calls and distributions received from fund managers and providing assistance to business units on impairment issues. Coordinate discussion and documentation of portfolio investment valuations with middle office.
- Involve in yearly audit planning meeting and assist external/internal auditors on audit queries. Ensure that the any differences between the local requirements and the Group's reporting under Singapore Financial Reporting Standards (FRS) be analyzed, adjusted, advised and reconciled for those overseas entities.
- Responsible for monthly and quarterly MAS reporting in Securities & Futures Act (SFA) Forms 1 & 5 and MAS Annex A & B. Prepare and submit FR Y-7 and Y-10 forms to US Federal Reserve Bank (FRB) on US related entities on quarterly/yearly basis.
- Possess good knowledge of International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS) and the ability to analyze and access its impacts on the financials on the entities.
- Ensure financial control standards are properly set and maintained. Assist with implementation of accounting policies and procedures.
- Demonstrate independence in liquidation of 3 companies and negotiated a lower fee for the Company which resulted in cost savings to the Bank.
- Identify ways to improve the process of extraction of data for MAS Annex A&B and reduced preparation time by more than 50%.

VOLVO EAST ASIA PTE LTD August 2007 to February 2008

Business Analyst

• Prepare management and AR reports (forecast, actual) for South East Asia. Coordinate quarter financial forecast and business plans and investigate variances.

SONY ELECTRONICS ASIA PACIFIC PTE LTD May 2004 to August 2007

Financial Analyst

- Prepare management reports for Pan Asia region and globally.
- Reviewed variances difference and perform trend analysis on sales companies' KPI.

HEWLETT-PACKARD FAR EAST PTE LTD May 2003 to May 2004

Data Analyst

• Provide analysis of the end-users' experience of software applications on the internet across Asia.